

# JORGE ODUBER

Statistician

## About Me

"Statistician graduated from the Central University of Venezuela with extensive experience in leading companies in the country, focused on obtaining answers through the use of statistical techniques that allow me to achieve my goal."



+584241359637



jorgeoduber@gmail.com



Av. San Sebastián, Qta Alexelly, Vargas, Vzla.

## LANGUAGE

- Spain
- English (Intermediate)

### **EXPERTISE**

- Experience in Data Science, data analysis, and visualization.
- Proficient in tools such as SAS, R Studio, Power BI, SPSS
- Indicator construction and application of statistical techniques
- Projection, and customersegmentation
- Report generation and market research
- Budget control and strategic decisionmaking

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Atenas Grupo Consultor Caracas-Venezuela 2022 - 2023

Developed socio-economic indicator using statistical techniques . Analyzed daily price basket to identify consumption patterns. Ensured representative sample for consumer consumption Projections employing statistical techniques and decision trees .

#### Consultores 21.

#### Caracas-Venezuela

2019 - 2021

Managed national telephone database for representative sampling. Developed precise methodologies for state-level sample sizing ensuring representativeness. Analyzed customer satisfaction indicators (NPS) using surveys and statistical techniques. Conducted statistical analysis for reliable projections and insights.

#### Banesco

#### Caracas-Venezuela

2016 - 2019

Performed data cross-referencing, mining and database cleaning for large datasets.

Calculated customer churn using SAS program.

Conducted customer segmentation based on banking customer characteristics using SAS, and SPSS.

#### Grifoven

## Colombia-Venezuela

2011 - 2016

Managed sales in Caracas, Barranquilla, and nationwide promotions. Developed clients conducted market studies and acquired new clients.

Led product marketing managed clients and prepared sales reports. Analyzed and projected sales using statistical models.

#### **CANTV**

#### Caracas-Venezuela

2009 - 2010

Compiling confidential quarterly market share reports for executive stakeholders.

Designing and implementing market indicators to evaluate industry performance and trends.

Conducting competitive market research studies to extract key insights.

•

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Central University of Venezuela

Bachelor's degree, Statistics 1996 - 2003

## **SKILLS SUMMARY**



#### **COURSES**

- Data Science and machine learning bootcamp with R studio (2023)
- Introduction to data analytics (2022)
- Introductionto statistical concepts
- Introduction to Anova, regression and logistic regression with SAS (2020)







# Polar Caracas-Venezuela 2007 - 2011

Expertise in compiling client portfolio, sales and theft incident reports to drive decision-making.

Proactively identifying synergies across company businesses to enhance profitability and reduce costs.

Proficient in market research, adapting market intelligence findings, and generating macro-level business statistics for strategic decision-making.

# Adriática de Seguros Caracas-Venezuela 2004 - 2007

Ensure regional compliance with set goals, while developing annual budget aligned with objectives.

Analyze trend charts to evaluate regional performance and implement corrective measures when necessary.

Coordinate broker segmentation and customer-focused strategies to maximize customer satisfaction and loyalty.

# Instituto nacional de Estadística Caracas-Venezuela 2000 - 2002

Oversee and validate census data collected by enumerators, ensuring accuracy and quality.

Supervise enumerators, providing guidance and support to adhere to protocols and standards.

Implement quality controls and analyze data reliability for census information assurance.

# Banco Cenrtral de Venezuela Caracas-Venezuela 1998 - 2000

Compile and analyze CPI data, tracking price changes of goods and services.

Validate and verify data collected by enumerators, ensuring accuracy and consistency.

Validate CPI weighting for accurate representation and evaluate its quality.